import{j as e}from"./index-KqHWGBVS.js";const t={sections:[{header:{text:e.jsxs(e.Fragment,{children:["Complete the sentences with ",e.jsx("b",{children:"do"})," or ",e.jsx("b",{children:"does"})]}),translation:e.jsxs(e.Fragment,{children:["Заполните предложения ",e.jsx("b",{children:"do"})," или ",e.jsx("b",{children:"does"})]})},global:{fill:{normalize:{ignorePunctmarks:!0},answers:{1:["do","i"],2:["does","i"]}}},exercises:[{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"What colour"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"1"},{text:"you like?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"Where"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"2"},{text:"she work?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"Where"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"1"},{text:"your parents live?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"What kind of films"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"1"},{text:"you prefer?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{rightAnswerRegexId:"2"},{text:"he play football at the weekends?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"How"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"1"},{text:"your friends spend their free time?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{rightAnswerRegexId:"2"},{text:"Allan have green eyes?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"What time"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"2"},{text:"she get from work?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"What school"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"1"},{text:"you study at?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{rightAnswerRegexId:"1"},{text:"you have breakfast in the morning?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"Where"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"1"},{text:"they put their key?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{rightAnswerRegexId:"2"},{text:"your son go to the school in the city?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{rightAnswerRegexId:"2"},{text:"this cat and that dog get on well?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{rightAnswerRegexId:"2"},{text:"your friend know any celebrities?"}]]},{type:"fill",lines:[[{text:"What subject"},{rightAnswerRegexId:"1"},{text:"you study at the university?"}]]}]},{header:{text:"Choose the correct option"},exercises:[{type:"test",question:"I ____ like shopping.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't",2:"doesn't",3:"aren't"}},{type:"test",question:"____ what you want?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does Betsy know",2:"Betsy knows",3:"Do Betsy knows"}},{type:"test",question:"Kitty and Lucy ____ my cats.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"My brother often ____ Mummy about the house.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"helps",2:"helpes",3:"help"}},{type:"test",question:"Tess ____ to the cinema every week.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"goes",2:"will goes",3:"go"}},{type:"test",question:"____ they ____ English well?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do ... speak",2:"Does ... speak",3:"Do ... speaks"}},{type:"test",question:"____ you from Canada?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"Angela's grandmother ____ from France.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"is",2:"am",3:"are"}},{type:"test",question:"9 What's the matter? You ____ very sad.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"look",2:"looks",3:"looking"}},{type:"test",question:"____ you ____ where your brother ____ ?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do ... know ... is",2:"Do ... know ... was",3:"Are ... know ... is"}},{type:"test",question:"I ____ that woman because I ____ French.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't understand ... don't know",2:"not understand ... don't know",3:"don't understand ... not know"}},{type:"test",question:"Patricia ____ English but he ____ Spanish.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"speaks ... doesn't speak",2:"speak ... not speak",3:"speaks ... doesn't speaks"}},{type:"test",question:"Winter is warm here. It ____ very seldom. But sometimes it ____.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"snows ... rains",2:"rain ... snows",3:"snow ... rain"}},{type:"test",question:"What time ____ she usually come home after school?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"does",2:"has",3:"do",4:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"I ____ not your mother.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"am",2:"is",3:"are"}},{type:"test",question:"We ____ a sofa, but we are going to buy it.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't have",2:"aren't have",3:"hasn't"}},{type:"test",question:"My mother ____ a bad backache.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"has got",2:"have got",3:"am"}},{type:"test",question:"____ your grandmother often ____ to the theatre?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does ... go",2:"Is ... go",3:"Do ... go"}},{type:"test",question:"They ____ French.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"____ you ____ any money? – Sorry, I ____.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do you have ... don't",2:"Have you got ... am not",3:"Do you have ... have got"}}]},{header:{text:"Choose the correct option"},exercises:[{type:"test",question:"Jace lives not far from us, but we ____ him often.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't see",2:"not see",3:"doesn't see"}},{type:"test",question:"Paul is very good at golf. He ______ every game.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"wins",2:"gets",3:"won"}},{type:"test",question:"____ any juice in the fridge?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does Pam have",2:"Do Pam has",3:"Have Pam got"}},{type:"test",question:"I ___ an actor.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"am",2:"is",3:"are"}},{type:"test",question:"My son Mark ____ apples, but he likes oranges.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"doesn't like",2:"not likes",3:"doesn't likes"}},{type:"test",question:"___ you play football? No, I ____.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do ... don't",2:"Do ... doesn't",3:"Are ... not"}},{type:"test",question:"Mary and her sister ____ wonderful hair.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"have got",2:"does",3:"has got"}},{type:"test",question:"____ Tara like books?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does",2:"Is",3:"Has"}},{type:"test",question:"Larry and I ______ for a company, which ______ computers.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"work ... produces",2:"works ... produces",3:"work ... produce"}},{type:"test",question:"______ you ______ where your son ______ ?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Do ... know ... is",2:"Do ... know ... was",3:"Are ... know ... is"}},{type:"test",question:"We ___ pupils.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"____ any brothers or sisters?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does mom have",2:"Have mom got",3:"Does mom has"}},{type:"test",question:"I ____ this book. Can you help me?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't understand",2:"doesn't understand",3:"understands"}},{type:"test",question:"____ Julia Santorini ____ French?",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Does ... speak",2:"Is ... speak",3:"Do ... speak"}},{type:"test",question:"Frank ___ a dentist.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"is",2:"am",3:"are"}},{type:"test",question:"His grandfather ______ him to school in his car.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"takes",2:"take",3:"taken"}},{type:"test",question:"My sister and I often _____ Mummy about the house.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"help",2:"helps",3:"helping"}},{type:"test",question:"They ___ Spanish.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}},{type:"test",question:"We _____ know Tom and Tom ____ know us.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"don't ... doesn't",2:"are not ... isn't",3:"do ... not"}},{type:"test",question:"Manchester and London ___ cities in England.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"are",2:"am",3:"is"}}]}]};export{t as default};
